<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motivation on Kamil Pro</title>
    <link>https://kamilpro.com/categories/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motivation on Kamil Pro</description>
    <image>
      <title>Kamil Pro</title>
      <url>https://kamilpro.com/109</url>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/109</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 21:23:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kamilpro.com/categories/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Need for energy – my short story of running</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/need-energy-short-story-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 21:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/need-energy-short-story-running/</guid>
      <description>This a quick story how sysadmin started running. I hope it will inspire you to do something with your body, mind and people around you. Yes, because once you’ll start feeling better, others around you will start feeling better as well.
Just a little over 6 months ago… That was November – rainy, windy and cold November. I was exhausted after months of pushing forward the work load. Our team was going through fundamental changes, and the last months towards November were nerve wracking, and there was no light at the end of the tunnel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do you check email every 2 minutes? Start batching your tasks</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/start-batching-your-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/start-batching-your-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Bump. A new email has just arrived. Have to check it. Now. I might reply to it earlier, but need to read it now.
Seriously, why?
While being on top of every single thing might sound super productive, it’s not. Being busy doesn’t mean that you’re productive. Being busy means you’re busy, got nothing to do with effectiveness.
This is the reason why you’d like to play it smart, and to organise your job into batches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Saturday is best to start new hobby.</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/why-saturday-is-best-to-start-new-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 06:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/why-saturday-is-best-to-start-new-hobby/</guid>
      <description>“I’m going to lose 10 KG”
“I’ll start exercising”
“I’ll crack on with my studies and get a better job”
Can you recall any of these? We prefer to set ourselves goals within certain time frame, like beginning of the year, month or week. That sort of fresh-start gets extra power as a statement, allows us to easily cut off the imperfect past from the all new and wonderful future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overloaded</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/overloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 09:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/overloaded/</guid>
      <description>Recently I’ve been writing about information overload. That we should avoid it, select only the best information.
Oh well, I have overloaded myself recently.
I slept 24 hours over the last 2 days! From 8 PM till 8AM. Children don’t sleep that much. My last 2 days had been like: Wake up, shower, work, coffee, home, dinner, coffee, sleep.
Exciting, isn’t it?
For the past 2 days my memory was like ROM – Read Only Memory – mission was to think clearly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-investment</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/self-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 22:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/self-investment/</guid>
      <description>I’m crazy about few things in my life. One of them is self-investment. Something what I do entirely for myself, because I am convinced that it will be beneficial to me, eventually.
At the beginning of my IT journey, I sacrificed a lot of time. There were whole weekends with computer as well as late nights during a week. I wasn’t aware that this could have been an actual investment, that I was working towards bettering my future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notification</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 19:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/notification/</guid>
      <description>I carry with me 2 phones – personal one and work one. On the first one, I store only personal stuff, while on the 0ther one everything what is work related.
I have been using my phones like probably most of the people – putting them on vibration while in the restaurants, office etc. so that the phones wouldn’t annoy people around me. But, something’s changed when I was sent for a business trip abroad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why certification matters?</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/why-certification-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/why-certification-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gained most of my experience by doing and working things out. Quite often I was reinventing the wheel and discovering already discovered lands. Well, that gave me a lot practice, and no doubts, made me who I am now. But how could I actually proof my skills?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
