<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Powershell - Category - Kamil Procyszyn</title>
        <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/categories/powershell/</link>
        <description>Powershell - Category - Kamil Procyszyn</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 18:27:18 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kprocyszyn.github.io/categories/powershell/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Restarting VSS Writers with PowerShell script</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 18:27:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[VSS Writers are responsible for backups – if they stop working, then backups might fail. The solution to that is restarting VSS Writers, but the problem here is that there are many, and at least out of the box, there’s no mechanism to make this automatic… but there’s PowerShell.
I’m not interested in your code, I just want to restart these VSS Writers In that case, head on to: mygithub, use the code and run:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Resolve IP and DNS with Powershell tool</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 21:40:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I’ve been asked to prepare a simple tool which would:
 Resolve IP address or DNS Return all results to table Import addresses from a file  The reason behind was to check how IP/DNS records change over the period of time, therefore there was a need for something like that:
 A file with all addresses in question Tool which could import all these addresses and resolve them Save the results into a new file  Once having at least a couple of files, the results could be compared.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Powershell – resolve full names to usernames from CSV file</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 14:03:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It’s unbelievable how long it took me to figure out this simple Powershell script, but yet it does the trick :).
Often you receive a request to do a certain action with a bunch of accounts, and (obviously) the list provided contains the full names rather usernames. Pain to do it manually, but yet we can utilise Powershell here.
What you need: CSV file, with only one column, and the header of the column must be called “Name”, if you prefer to use something different, simply amend Name in line 6 to reflect your header.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
