<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>thoughts on Kamil Pro</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on Kamil Pro</description><image><title>Kamil Pro</title><url>https://kamilpro.github.io/logo.png</url><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/logo.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Kamil Procyszyn</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 19:47:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kamilpro.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I’m really missing time before the Internet.</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/im-really-missing-time-internet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 19:47:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/im-really-missing-time-internet/</guid><description>Because software was working without the need of downloading tons of patches. Why do we actually need to update software in the first place?
In the past, the only way to obtain a software was by delivering the physical media to the recipient. There was a cost of media itself and shipment (and probably much more of which I’m not aware of), it couldn’t be cheap. While comparing to the current times, it is just a matter of uploading an update to the server and push to users.</description></item><item><title>On time – to be or not to be</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</guid><description>We live in a time driven world. We to try to maximise 24 hours every day. Time wasting is not an option.
Therefore we try to squeeze as much as possible in a schedule. Beginning from very morning.
Every morning we start fairly the same, fulfilling daily ritual. Make up, news, coffee – ready, steady, go – everything what make us ready to make a public appearance .
So it’s 8 am, and we are certainly ready to leave.</description></item><item><title>The kill joy, ready made type</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 22:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</guid><description>What an easy life when you are an ignorant!
Dull face. Knows all football matches. Actually, this fellow made an art from sitting in front of a TV with a 4-for-£4 pack and trying to prove that this is his life passion. I think I could made another passion from observing clouds in the garden. I would watch them for hours while they change their shapes, move around in the sky, still sitting in the chair and observing them pointlessly.</description></item><item><title>27 was a great number</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/27-was-a-great-number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 21:58:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/27-was-a-great-number/</guid><description>but I’m certain that 28 will be even better!
Yes, yesterday was my birthday. Another great year has passed but this time with a wonderful woman next to my side. It&amp;#8217;s unbelievable how many good things have happened in the last 365 days. I could now start telling you and show off&amp;#8230; but not on this occasion, this is a celebration time! On the days like these, I think about changing my settings to neutral, stop rushing and just sit calmly and wait for what comes next&amp;#8230;anything&amp;#8230; No.</description></item><item><title>Apps, and their impact on the smart phone</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/apps-impact-smart-phone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 09:45:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/apps-impact-smart-phone/</guid><description>When we buy a new phone, manufacturers advertise it always as a super fast with superb colours and a long lasting battery.
Usually it’s true, which we can confirm just after the unboxing ritual when we hold our brand new device in the hands.
It’s shiny, without scratches, with a specific smell, plus it’s really fast and battery lasts very long.
Until… we actually start using the phone, by this I mean installing the whole lot of our favourite apps.</description></item><item><title>Overloaded</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/overloaded/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 09:32:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/overloaded/</guid><description>Recently I’ve been writing about information overload. That we should avoid it, select only the best information.
Oh well, I have overloaded myself recently.
I slept 24 hours over the last 2 days! From 8 PM till 8AM. Children don’t sleep that much. My last 2 days had been like: Wake up, shower, work, coffee, home, dinner, coffee, sleep.
Exciting, isn’t it?
For the past 2 days my memory was like ROM – Read Only Memory – mission was to think clearly.</description></item><item><title>Whatever floats your boat…</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/whatever-floats-your-boat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 21:57:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/whatever-floats-your-boat/</guid><description>How many times I’ve put my all enthusiasm into something, being convinced that it was the right thing.
Hundreds, maybe thousands of times.
How many time afterwards I have realised that my belief was completely wrong. Like 100% wrong. Like back to front feeling.
I think the most difficult is the moment of making a decision. That very moment when it’s time to commit to a long standing decision. The second when it’s time to reveal self and go public.</description></item><item><title>Headphones</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/headphones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:25:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/headphones/</guid><description>At home while writing, photo editing or just for fun. At work when I need to focus and be effective. At the time when I need a boost or completely opposite – when looking for a way to calm down. Headphones accompany me throughout the day.
There is something about sound that keeps me going. When I need to keep up and focus on something certain, I listen to some energy energetic music.</description></item><item><title>Self-investment</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/self-investment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 22:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/self-investment/</guid><description>I’m crazy about few things in my life. One of them is self-investment. Something what I do entirely for myself, because I am convinced that it will be beneficial to me, eventually.
At the beginning of my IT journey, I sacrificed a lot of time. There were whole weekends with computer as well as late nights during a week. I wasn’t aware that this could have been an actual investment, that I was working towards bettering my future.</description></item><item><title>Routine</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/routine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 22:35:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/routine/</guid><description>They say that habits are our second nature. Things which we do repeatedly are like pre-programmed functions which trigger specific time or action.
Morning coffee. I simply cannot start the day without a cup of a real coffee. That was the reason why I bought the actual bean to coffee machine, because of the taste and smell of real coffee. Prepared in the exact way I like it.
This week I’ve ran out of the time in the morning and couldn’t make my favourite coffee, so I used the instant one.</description></item><item><title>Rely</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/rely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/rely/</guid><description>Trust, hope, relationship. Words which make us feel good, because we can rely on others.
I remember when sometime ago, I needed to push a new software to about 50 computers. As always, with that kind of operation, there was a very limited time to do this.
In normal situation, there is deployment solution in place – a server which distributes the software in an automated way. Obviously, as an administrator I need to prepare the whole process – finding installers, commands and switches for these software and even writing scripts.</description></item><item><title>No pain, no gain.</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/no-pain-no-gain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 21:09:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/no-pain-no-gain/</guid><description>How many times petty things have ruined your day? Or people? Or, even, yourself? Just admit it.
We can take a lot. Our minds are like massive hard drives which store data in a form of memories, feelings and thoughts.
Did you know that a human is able to erase certain bad memories or push them right back, deep in our subconscious? For example, women are going though unbelievable pain while giving a birth.</description></item><item><title>Share</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/share/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 22:05:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/share/</guid><description>I remember like when I was 10-ish and had been trying to fix my first computer. There was no Internet, there was no one really to ask for advice or share the knowledge with me. It took me days, and at the very end, I found that I didn’t have essential drivers to make my computer really usable. Did I mention that the Internet wasn’t available yet?
I had to figure this out, and it took me ridiculous amount of time to achieve such a basic task like reinstalling an operating system.</description></item><item><title>Influence</title><link>https://kamilpro.github.io/influence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.github.io/influence/</guid><description>A friend visited us yesterday. There was a nice cake, coffee, dinner and conversations thoughtout the night.
Suddenly the ladies started to talk about navigation apps on mobile devices. K. was complaining about high data usage during browsing on the Internet. J. suggested her to try Here maps as it is free and allows to download the maps, therefore data is completely not needed for navigation to work, plus it is really accurate app.</description></item></channel></rss>