<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feat on Kamil Pro</title>
    <link>https://kamilpro.com/tags/feat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feat on Kamil Pro</description>
    <image>
      <title>Kamil Pro</title>
      <url>https://kamilpro.com/105</url>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/105</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 18:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kamilpro.com/tags/feat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Restarting VSS Writers with PowerShell script</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 18:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</guid>
      <description>VSS Writers are responsible for backups – if they stop working, then backups might fail. The solution to that is restarting VSS Writers, but the problem here is that there are many, and at least out of the box, there’s no mechanism to make this automatic… but there’s PowerShell.
I’m not interested in your code, I just want to restart these VSS Writers In that case, head on to: mygithub, use the code and run:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolve IP and DNS with Powershell tool</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been asked to prepare a simple tool which would:
Resolve IP address or DNS Return all results to table Import addresses from a file The reason behind was to check how IP/DNS records change over the period of time, therefore there was a need for something like that:
A file with all addresses in question Tool which could import all these addresses and resolve them Save the results into a new file Once having at least a couple of files, the results could be compared.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PNPUTIL – how to add drivers to the Windows image</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</guid>
      <description>Drivers – that’s what makes a harmony between hardware and software. Appropriate drivers can make a huge difference between computer’s performance, stability and even temperature. Therefore it’s super important to make sure you’ve got up-to-date files included with your image or Windows installation.
We are going to review PNPUTIL tool – the versatile tool for handling drivers within the Windows.
Why do you need PNPUTIL? Yes, why bother with some command line tool (PNPUTIL is command line only) when there are dedicated installers and device manager?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare Windows 10 1607 image</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later every company will come to the point when using standard Windows image is just not enough. Manual installation, fetching all updates or installing software etc. etc. takes time, and in IT, we really can use that time for something way more productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
