<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Windows on Kamil Pro</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/categories/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Kamil Pro</description><image><title>Kamil Pro</title><url>https://kamilpro.com/logo.png</url><link>https://kamilpro.com/logo.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Kamil Procyszyn</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kamilpro.com/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Software with Chocolatey - Automate installation and updates of your applications</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</guid><description>Software management is not trivial task. Preparing for silent deployment is challenging, and even if you manage to install the application, how to keep it up to date?
Chocolatey is package manager for Windows, that can fully automate lifecycle of your software.
In this video, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to install Chocolatey, then how to find software, install it and finally keeping it up to date - all coming with free open-source license.</description></item><item><title>Deploying software with GPO</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/deploying-software-with-gpo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 14:25:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/deploying-software-with-gpo/</guid><description>Having software consistently deployed across the fleet of computers is one of the key points that can be automated.
If I have a choice (and it makes sense), I will always choose GPO over any other solution because it’s embedded into Active Directory thus not requiring installation, learning and maintenance of additional management tool.
MSI – Software Installation One of the main advantages of MSI installers is that in 99% of cases you can just use the “Software Installation” option in GPO, and GPO will take care of the silent installation.</description></item><item><title>Prepare Hyper-V template of Windows Server 2016/2019</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-hyper-v-template-of-windows-server-2016-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:52:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-hyper-v-template-of-windows-server-2016-2019/</guid><description>Deploying a new server is always fun! Well, at least the part after ISO download, installation, patching. Having said that, why not create a template so that you jump right into the fun?
So we are essentially going to create a preconfigured VHDX file that can be attached to the newly created VM, and it will take you straight to the login screen.
What’s needed Windows server or Windows 10 with Hyper-V role and management tools enabled Windows Assessment and Deployment Toolkit (ADK) – I always pick the latest version available, at the moment of writing this – Windows 10, version 1903 – is latest.</description></item><item><title>Backup Exec – cataloging multiple tapes with a single tape drive</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/backup-exec-cataloging-multiple-tapes-with-a-single-tape-drive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/backup-exec-cataloging-multiple-tapes-with-a-single-tape-drive/</guid><description>Recently I’ve had a request to restore a certain backup from the old backup tapes. We’ve had a new Backup exec installation which didn’t have the catalogue/record of these tapes nor the actual tape drive to recover them – I knew it was going to be one in the world task. And the hell it was.
Locating tapes in the storage unit was a pure joy – no need to go to the gym after this.</description></item><item><title>Use Windows Server as iSCSI target with ESXi</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/use-windows-server-as-iscsi-target-with-esxi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:54:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/use-windows-server-as-iscsi-target-with-esxi/</guid><description>The task: to move a virtual machine from one ESXi to another. The ESXis are on two completely separate networks. VM size is 5.5 TB, with one file being 5TB.
The problem: VM cannot be started due to maxed out resources. There’s no NAS or any other means of storage where the files could be transferred to. From previous experience, I knew that transfer over SSH or USB would be well too slow, as the task was time critical.</description></item><item><title>Resolve IP and DNS with Powershell tool</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</guid><description>I’ve been asked to prepare a simple tool which would:
Resolve IP address or DNS Return all results to table Import addresses from a file The reason behind was to check how IP/DNS records change over the period of time, therefore there was a need for something like that:
A file with all addresses in question Tool which could import all these addresses and resolve them Save the results into a new file Once having at least a couple of files, the results could be compared.</description></item><item><title>Ultimate Windows Update fix</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/ultimate-windows-update-fix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 22:12:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/ultimate-windows-update-fix/</guid><description>The reason I manage hundreds of workstations working on various Windows versions. As we know, Windows (and other Microsoft’s software) is updated monthly. While usually the process is just working fine, sometimes it simply doesn’t want to work.
And yes, probably Google is your best friend here… but really, who has time to search for the solution, and apply it, manually, if there is more than 1 computer?
Use the script I used technet, different posts and own knowledge of fixing that kind of issues.</description></item><item><title>Powershell – resolve full names to usernames from CSV file</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 14:03:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</guid><description>It’s unbelievable how long it took me to figure out this simple Powershell script, but yet it does the trick :).
Often you receive a request to do a certain action with a bunch of accounts, and (obviously) the list provided contains the full names rather usernames. Pain to do it manually, but yet we can utilise Powershell here.
What you need: CSV file, with only one column, and the header of the column must be called “Name”, if you prefer to use something different, simply amend Name in line 6 to reflect your header.</description></item><item><title>Add any drivers to Windows – on example of GPU drivers</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</guid><description>Today we are going to inject drivers into the Windows image with the help of built-in tools in Windows.
What do you need? Just a few things:
Any hardware to which you’d like drivers to be added to Reference computer with the hardware attached to it Drivers Windows image which is going to be deployed I think there’s not much to explain, so let’s analyse the actual process.
What we are going to do?</description></item><item><title>Mastering PNPUTIL – how to add drivers to the Windows image</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</guid><description>Drivers – that’s what makes a harmony between hardware and software. Appropriate drivers can make a huge difference between computer’s performance, stability and even temperature. Therefore it’s super important to make sure you’ve got up-to-date files included with your image or Windows installation.
We are going to review PNPUTIL tool – the versatile tool for handling drivers within the Windows.
Why do you need PNPUTIL? Yes, why bother with some command line tool (PNPUTIL is command line only) when there are dedicated installers and device manager?</description></item><item><title>How to prepare Windows 10 1607 image</title><link>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sooner or later every company will come to the point when using standard Windows image is just not enough. Manual installation, fetching all updates or installing software etc. etc. takes time, and in IT, we really can use that time for something way more productive.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>