<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Windows - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/windows/</link><description>Windows - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Kamil Procyszyn</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/windows/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Software with Chocolatey - Automate installation and updates of your applications</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</guid><description>Software management is not trivial task. Preparing for silent deployment is challenging, and even if you manage to install the application, how to keep it up to date?
Chocolatey is package manager for Windows, that can fully automate lifecycle of your software.
In this video, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to install Chocolatey, then how to find software, install it and finally keeping it up to date - all coming with free open-source license.</description></item><item><title>Add any drivers to Windows – on example of GPU drivers</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:53:05 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/jeff-sheldon-3221.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Today we are going to inject drivers into the Windows image with the help of built-in tools in Windows.
What do you need? Just a few things:
Any hardware to which you’d like drivers to be added to Reference computer with the hardware attached to it Drivers Windows image which is going to be deployed I think there’s not much to explain, so let’s analyse the actual process.</description></item><item><title>Mastering PNPUTIL – how to add drivers to the Windows image</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/wil-stewart-21815.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Drivers – that’s what makes a harmony between hardware and software. Appropriate drivers can make a huge difference between computer’s performance, stability and even temperature. Therefore it’s super important to make sure you’ve got up-to-date files included with your image or Windows installation.
We are going to review PNPUTIL tool – the versatile tool for handling drivers within the Windows.
Why do you need PNPUTIL? Yes, why bother with some command line tool (PNPUTIL is command line only) when there are dedicated installers and device manager?</description></item><item><title>Why certification matters?</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/why-certification-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:42:35 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/why-certification-matters/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gained most of my experience by doing and working things out. Quite often I was reinventing the wheel and discovering already discovered lands. Well, that gave me a lot practice, and no doubts, made me who I am now. But how could I actually proof my skills?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>