<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>sysadmin - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/sysadmin/</link><description>sysadmin - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Kamil Procyszyn</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/sysadmin/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Software with Chocolatey - Automate installation and updates of your applications</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/managing-software-with-chocolatey-automate-installation-and-updates-of-your-applications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/managing-software-with-chocolatey-automate-installation-and-updates-of-your-applications/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/feat.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Software management is not trivial task. Preparing for silent deployment is challenging, and even if you manage to install the application, how to keep it up to date?
Chocolatey is package manager for Windows, that can fully automate lifecycle of your software.
In this video, I&rsquo;ll show you how to install Chocolatey, then how to find software, install it and finally keeping it up to date - all coming with free open-source license.]]></description></item><item><title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#11] – Variables</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-11-variables/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-11-variables/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Variables.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>In this lesson we’re going to learn how what Variables are, why it’s good to use them and how to actually create them. We will then assign various values to variables to and use them solely, and in parameters.
We will also have a look at foreach loop so that we can e.g. ping multiple computers using single variable with multiple objects in it.
Exercises Use Get-Command to find all commands that allow you to manage variables.</description></item><item><title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#10] – Remote management with PowerShell</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Remoting.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this lesson we’re going to learn how to do one-to-one and one-to-many remote management with PowerShell. There’s no need for telnet, ssh or psexec as PowerShell has its own protocol that’s built in right into Windows. We will look at how to create interactive sessions and send commands to multiple servers at once.
Exercises  With Enter-PSSesion, Remote to remote server and&nbsp; restart &#8220;Windows update&#8221; service   With Invoke-Command find out the remote computers last boot up/startup time   List all running processes on remote server without using Enter-PsSession or Invoke-Command   If you have a Domain Controller available, use Invoke-Command to list all computers on that network (you can use * for filter), remember that you need to provide all necessary parameters with your command in the script block so command just runs and doesn&#8217;t prompt for any additional information.]]></description></item><item><title>Sysadmin’s tools – what I have installed on my laptop</title><link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/sysadmins-tools-what-i-have-installed-on-my-laptop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:40:21 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/sysadmins-tools-what-i-have-installed-on-my-laptop/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rob-lambert-64186-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>We need tools to make our work. Either it’s notepad and paper, a hammer (for server’s hard reset… just joking) or some sophisticated and bespoke peace of hardware – we as professionals need tools to make our work better, or even possible.
Since working as IT person, there are many software tools I need to do my day to day tasks, thus here’s the list of pieces of software I’ve been finding useful.</description></item></channel></rss>