<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>internet - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</title>
        <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/internet/</link>
        <description>internet - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:57:20 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/internet/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#19] – Websites and APIs</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:57:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[PowerShell is a great server automation tool, but what about Internet and any other web served services?
As it turns out, PowerShell is great in scrapping websites and consuming APIs – and it’s been one of the main development areas of the tool in the last couple of years.
In this lesson we are going to see how to use PowerShell to download files, scrap websites, discover links.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>I’m really missing time before the Internet.</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/im-really-missing-time-internet/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 19:47:22 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/im-really-missing-time-internet/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Because software was working without the need of downloading tons of patches. Why do we actually need to update software in the first place?
In the past, the only way to obtain a software was by delivering the physical media to the recipient. There was a cost of media itself and shipment (and probably much more of which I’m not aware of), it couldn’t be cheap. While comparing to the current times, it is just a matter of uploading an update to the server and push to users.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Share</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/share/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 22:05:34 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/share/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I remember like when I was 10-ish and had been trying to fix my first computer. There was no Internet, there was no one really to ask for advice or share the knowledge with me. It took me days, and at the very end, I found that I didn’t have essential drivers to make my computer really usable. Did I mention that the Internet wasn’t available yet?
I had to figure this out, and it took me ridiculous amount of time to achieve such a basic task like reinstalling an operating system.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Spam</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/spam/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 21:30:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/spam/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Spam. Spam everywhere. There isn’t a day without it. Without bombarding us with plenty of information. Way too much of information.
While the original – email spam – is well handled by email providers, the other sources are not.
On social media – there is plenty of shared stuff which someone (I hope so!) thought was worth of sharing. News is all over the place – starting from daily free newspapers, through radio and TV and ending up on the Internet.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
