<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Me &amp;amp; People - Category - Kamil Procyszyn</title>
        <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/categories/me-amp-people/</link>
        <description>Me &amp;amp; People - Category - Kamil Procyszyn</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Kamil Procyszyn</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:42:49 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kprocyszyn.github.io/categories/me-amp-people/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>2018 summary</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/2018-summary/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:42:49 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/2018-summary/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nordwood-themes-467442-unsplash.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Here we are, again. Same symbolic time of the year.
I find it perfect to review the past 12 months and have a think about it.
I broke it down into three sections – professional, personal and what didn’t work out. So, let’s go!
Professional Learnt PowerShell – I think it was the biggest achievement career wise this year. It’s hard to put this in formalised matter, or any sort of figure – but the change of my mindset is the biggest one.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Blog is changing</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/blog-is-changing/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 07:30:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/blog-is-changing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1464963160608-a6834f70b421.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>My idea of this place has been changing since I’ve brought it up. It wasn’t even my first blog, in fact, it was a third one. But the main difference was I wanted to get to the world this time. Don’t just write for the sake of writing.
Very first version of this website was more like a business card or a CV, rather than a blog. I don’t say how proud I was, but also must admit how wrong I was.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>On time – to be or not to be</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 21:39:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1468169019754-e97ba70dafb6.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>We live in a time driven world. We to try to maximise 24 hours every day. Time wasting is not an option.
Therefore we try to squeeze as much as possible in a schedule. Beginning from very morning.
Every morning we start fairly the same, fulfilling daily ritual. Make up, news, coffee – ready, steady, go – everything what make us ready to make a public appearance .
So it’s 8 am, and we are certainly ready to leave.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Less is more</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/less-is-more/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 17:59:54 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/less-is-more/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1470343740979-20b904b850da.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>We live in a cram-full world, full of anything we could possibly imagine.</p>
<p>Having a choice is a great thing – I can pick stuff which really suits myself. In case I need, say, a teal corner 4 seater bed sofa, it’s just a matter of time and money I am prepared to spend, until I get one.</p>
<p>But what happens when I don’t have too many options? When there are 2 things which really suit me, but say, I’ve got space just for 1 sofa?</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>The kill joy, ready made type</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 22:02:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1470688090067-6d429c0b2600.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>What an easy life when you are an ignorant!
Dull face. Knows all football matches. Actually, this fellow made an art from sitting in front of a TV with a 4-for-£4 pack and trying to prove that this is his life passion. I think I could made another passion from observing clouds in the garden. I would watch them for hours while they change their shapes, move around in the sky, still sitting in the chair and observing them pointlessly.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>27 was a great number</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/27-was-a-great-number/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 21:58:56 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/27-was-a-great-number/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[but I’m certain that 28 will be even better!
Yes, yesterday was my birthday. Another great year has passed but this time with a wonderful woman next to my side.It&#8217;s unbelievable how many good things have happened in the last 365 days. I could now start telling you and show off&#8230; but not on this occasion, this is a celebration time!On the days like these, I think about changing my settings to neutral, stop rushing and just sit calmly and wait for what comes next&#8230;anything&#8230;No.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Whatever floats your boat…</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/whatever-floats-your-boat/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 21:57:25 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/whatever-floats-your-boat/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1456618054495-a9c763090b53.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>How many times I’ve put my all enthusiasm into something, being convinced that it was the right thing.
Hundreds, maybe thousands of times.
How many time afterwards I have realised that my belief was completely wrong. Like 100% wrong. Like back to front feeling.
I think the most difficult is the moment of making a decision. That very moment when it’s time to commit to a long standing decision. The second when it’s time to reveal self and go public.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Headphones</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/headphones/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:25:29 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/headphones/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/photo-1457305237443-44c3d5a30b89.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>At home while writing, photo editing or just for fun. At work when I need to focus and be effective. At the time when I need a boost or completely opposite – when looking for a way to calm down. Headphones accompany me throughout the day.
There is something about sound that keeps me going. When I need to keep up and focus on something certain, I listen to some energy energetic music.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Routine</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/routine/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 22:35:35 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/routine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/photo-1422433555807-2559a27433bd.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>They say that habits are our second nature. Things which we do repeatedly are like pre-programmed functions which trigger specific time or action.
Morning coffee. I simply cannot start the day without a cup of a real coffee. That was the reason why I bought the actual bean to coffee machine, because of the taste and smell of real coffee. Prepared in the exact way I like it.
This week I’ve ran out of the time in the morning and couldn’t make my favourite coffee, so I used the instant one.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Rely</title>
    <link>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/rely/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:49:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://kprocyszyn.github.io/rely/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/photo-1468345096048-fdb10393b472.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Trust, hope, relationship. Words which make us feel good, because we can rely on others.
I remember when sometime ago, I needed to push a new software to about 50 computers. As always, with that kind of operation, there was a very limited time to do this.
In normal situation, there is deployment solution in place – a server which distributes the software in an automated way. Obviously, as an administrator I need to prepare the whole process – finding installers, commands and switches for these software and even writing scripts.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
