<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kamil Pro</title>
    <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kamil Pro</description>
    <image>
      <title>Kamil Pro</title>
      <url>https://kamilpro.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kamilpro.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Health</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/pages/health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/posts/pages/health/</guid>
      <description>For several years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my health - with goal of staying healthy as long as possible. It all started with working on sleep, which was followed by jogging, nutrition etc. where at this point it has become a part of my identity.
The goal here is to keep this post as a baseline for comparing myself in the future, how much I drifted or improved over time, and then share to the any other person who wants work on themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at PsDayUk 2023</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2023/speaking-at-psdayuk-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2023/speaking-at-psdayuk-2023/</guid>
      <description>Side note, I was meant to publish this back in March 2023&amp;hellip;
When I attended my first PowerShell meetup back in 2017, I had no idea it would lead me to where I am today.
Fast forward to 3rd of March 2023, I was privileged to speak and share my knowledge with other #PowerShell enthusiasts at #PsDayUk conference. I presented the PowerShell based web server and web framework, which enables anyone familiar with the language, to create web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1000 Subscribers!</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2023/1000-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2023/1000-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just passed 1000 subscribers on my #YouTube channel - thank you! https://lnkd.in/e6mBpUZA
Back in 2020 I have started a little experiment and since then it has been slowly growing and growing. I wanted to share my knowledge and experience with like-minded IT professionals. I wanted to create a community where people could come to learn more about #powershell and how to become modern #sysadmin, while being free to ask any questions on the topic!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sysadmin to DevOps - My PowerShell ignited story</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2022/sysadmin-to-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2022/sysadmin-to-devops/</guid>
      <description>My story on how I turned from Sysadmin to DevOps engineer, with PowerShell driving my journey!
It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to think that 5 years ago I couldn&amp;rsquo;t code, and one tweet simply started a snowball effect on my career.
I wanted to document this moment in my life as I&amp;rsquo;ve passed Azure DevOps engineer exam and been working as DevOps engineer - something I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even about thinking without PowerShell and its great community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Software with Chocolatey - Automate installation and updates of your applications</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2021/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/posts/2021/managing-software-with-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>Software management is not trivial task. Preparing for silent deployment is challenging, and even if you manage to install the application, how to keep it up to date?
Chocolatey is package manager for Windows, that can fully automate lifecycle of your software.
In this video, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to install Chocolatey, then how to find software, install it and finally keeping it up to date - all coming with free open-source license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#20] – Next Steps with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-20-next-steps-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-20-next-steps-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations! This is 20th and last lesson in the course – and my aim here is to show you various paths you can take your PowerShell journey to.
I’m going to show what else you can do within PowerShell itself, as well how to keep up-to-day plus – what other doors writing code has opened for you – I’d love to hear back about this!
I hope you’ve enjoyed the course so far and it will be helped you in some way – either solve a problem, got promotion, or simply learnt something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#19] – Websites and APIs</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a great server automation tool, but what about Internet and any other web served services?
As it turns out, PowerShell is great in scrapping websites and consuming APIs – and it’s been one of the main development areas of the tool in the last couple of years.
In this lesson we are going to see how to use PowerShell to download files, scrap websites, discover links.
We will then use an API of PasswordPusher (pwpush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#18] – Working with text strings</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-18-working-with-text-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 17:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-18-working-with-text-strings/</guid>
      <description>Although PowerShell treats everything as object - including text strings - working with text might be particularly difficult - at least when first approached.
In this lesson we are going to have a closer look at what is possible with built in text methods and see how these can help us e.g. by extracting a substring of text.
PowerShell can also be great at parsing log files - we will use Select-String to quickly filter out the lines of text with the phrase we are looking for e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#17] – Scripting part 4 – parameters, running remotely and formatting</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-17-scripting-part-4-parameters-running-remotely-and-formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-17-scripting-part-4-parameters-running-remotely-and-formatting/</guid>
      <description>In the last part of scripting series, we will make the script to be able to query remote machines, e.g. servers.
We will also check how to add parameters to the script (and configure the default value of parameter) so that user will able to pass the parameter name like in a standard PowerShell cmdlet.
Finally, we are going to format the script so that it looks more reliable and make some refactoring so that the logic is simpler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#16] – Scripting part 3 – Add-Member and network</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-16-scripting-part-3-add-member-and-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 19:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-16-scripting-part-3-add-member-and-network/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we are taking our script further by adding details about IP configuration and last installed hotfixes.
But it turns out, the networking information is not that shallow as it seems at the first glance – thus I’ll show you how to retrieve the information from the configuration.
We will also look on how to reuse our already created object so that we don’t need to duplicate code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#15] – Scripting part 2 – IF and psobject</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-15-scripting-part-2-if-and-psobject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 17:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-15-scripting-part-2-if-and-psobject/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we carry on writing the scripting by gathering requirements and putting them together as comments in code.
Then we will retrieve OS information with the help of WMI and display it on the screen with Write-Host.
Although using Write-Host is easy to use, it doesn’t really allow us to do very much e.g. we cannot export information to the CSV, therefore we change it and start using custom PSObject – that way our script will start returning information like a regular PowerShell command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#14] – Scripting – Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-14-scripting-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-14-scripting-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we will be preparing our workstation for writing PowerShell scripts. We will start by enabling RSAT and then install Visual Studio Code which is a recommended and free PowerShell code editor.
We will then have a look at the basic function of VS Code and create a simple “Hello World” script.
Exercises If you haven’t followed along, you definitely would like to install VS Code and create a *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#13] – Is PowerShell secure?</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-13-is-powershell-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-13-is-powershell-secure/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we will have a look on PowerShell built in security features and how it differs from e.g. BAT files.
We will then have a look how execution policy can help to control on what basis the PowerShell scripts can be executed.
At the end, we will configure some GPOs to control the execution and transcription of scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#12] – WMI – Windows Management Instrumentation</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-12-wmi-windows-management-instrumentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-12-wmi-windows-management-instrumentation/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we learn how to use PowerShell to access WMI (Windows Management Instrumentation), so that we can gain often hidden or obscure information.
We will then use WMI Explorer graphical tool to ease discovering all possible classes and instances that WMI provides.
Finally, we will use WMI queries to add another level of granularity in GPO so that we can target very specific computers in it.
Exercises There’s a WMI class that lists all the installed software – find it and list all currently installed software with PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#11] – Variables</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-11-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-11-variables/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we’re going to learn how what Variables are, why it’s good to use them and how to actually create them. We will then assign various values to variables to and use them solely, and in parameters.
We will also have a look at foreach loop so that we can e.g. ping multiple computers using single variable with multiple objects in it.
Exercises Use Get-Command to find all commands that allow you to manage variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#10] – Remote management with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson we’re going to learn how to do one-to-one and one-to-many remote management with PowerShell. There’s no need for telnet, ssh or psexec as PowerShell has its own protocol that’s built in right into Windows. We will look at how to create interactive sessions and send commands to multiple servers at once.
Exercises Notes Enable-Psremoting Enter-PSSesion ps-svr1 Hostname Get-Service GIP # I can even run commands that are not available on my source machine Get-ADDomainController Get-ADUser Exit or Exit-PSSession # Caution about double hoping Invoke-Command Invoke-Command -computerName ps-svr1 -command { get-service} # Invoke command executes commands on the remote comptuers and brings back the results # Can you tell a difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#9] – Setting up Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-9-setting-up-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 12:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-9-setting-up-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>Exercises On domain controller, find module that allows to manage Active Directory List all the Active Directory users List members of “Enterprise Administrators” Find the feature name for Windows Server Backup and install it with PowerShell Commands ### Server # Check IP configuration # Show steps in Server how to install # Check hostname Hostname # Rename server Rename-Computer ps-svr1 # Restart computer Reboot-computer # Get-WindowsFeature # Install-WindowsFeature Install-WindowsFeature -Name AD-Domain-Services -IncludeManagementTools Install-ADDSForest -DomainName posh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#8] – Manage everything with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-8-manage-everything-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-8-manage-everything-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Exercises Can you uninstall module that was installed with Install-Module? Confirm your answer with Get-Module -ListAvaiable Can you update the installed module? Perhaps, you’d like to install version 1.0.0.0 of SNMP module, how can you force Install-Module to do so? Install-Module error If you encounter the issue with downloading modules, run this commandlet as a temporary workaround (it must be applied every time the shell is restarted):
Source of solution, and also permanent solution can be found at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#7] – Formatting output</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-7-formatting-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 12:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-7-formatting-output/</guid>
      <description>Exercises Send output of any commandlet, e.g. get service to Printer
Lesson notes # So far, we&amp;#39;ve been using default PowerShell behaviour for formatting output # Although in the last lesson we did filtering data with Where-Object and Select-Object # We didn&amp;#39;t really focus on how data is presented on the screen. Let&amp;#39;s see what can be done here. # Let&amp;#39;s have a look at local Get-LocalGroup Get-LocalGroup | Format-List #Alias is FL #Like with Select-Object, we can specify properties we&amp;#39;re after Get-LocalGroup | fl -Property name,sid #Another example when List might be easier to read then table Get-CimInstance win32_ComputerSystem ## Format Table #ipconfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#6] – Filtering output</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-6-filtering-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-6-filtering-output/</guid>
      <description>Exercises List all services that are stopped List all service that are stopped and they name begins with W Display only the Display Name of services that stopped and their name begins with W Lesson notes ### Filtering # Some commands accept wild cards in the search or have a filter parameter Get-Service -Name w*,b* #But there&amp;#39;s more universal method, based on property names Get-Service | Where-Object -Filter {$_.Status -eq &amp;#39;running&amp;#39; } #So let&amp;#39;s break it down #Where-Object allows to filter out the incoming object based on the comparation operator #Most popular operators are: -eq - Equals -ne - Not equals -gt - Greather than -lt - Less then -le - Less than or equal -ge - Greater than or equal -Like -Not like #There are more many, you can check these help topics: Help about_Operators Help about_Comparison_Operators #$_ is current object; it&amp;#39;s what we&amp;#39;re piping in our case Get-Service # .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#5] – Providers</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-5-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-5-providers/</guid>
      <description>Exercises Create a folder in root of C: with the name of PowerShell Create a file inside the folder with the name of your choice and no content Retrieve all items from Env: drive Check the version of Notepad.exe in Windows directory Discover current Windows build version by registry property: HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows NT\CurrentVersion Notes from the lesson # Provider allows to access some data storage (e.g. File system, registry, remote system, Active Directory) # This concept might sound a bit abstract at first, but becomes very straight forward once you&amp;#39;ve used it for a while # Provider once connected to the data storage, kind of &amp;#34;mounts&amp;#34; it like a network drive, allowing to browse and manage it # Once the storage is mounted PowerShell creates so called PSDrive # Let&amp;#39;s review available providers Get-Psprovider # Let&amp;#39;s review some PSDrives Get-PSDrive # A quick refresher how file system is organised: Drives, Folders, Files # Since PowerShell connects to many different file data storages, it uses the generic term Item and specifies with type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#4] – Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-4-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-4-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Exercises There’s one particular command that allows you output anything from shell to file, find that command and use with any commands like Get-Service or Get-Process. Does it behave differently than Export-CSV?
Programs often use CSV but don’t use comma for delimiter – try to exporting to CSV but change the delimiter
Can you print directly from shell? See if there are any commands available and if so, print some Event Logs!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#3] – Running Commands</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-2-running-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-2-running-commands/</guid>
      <description>Exercises Display a list of all services that start with the letter W Display all processes (you might need to use Help to discover the right command. Remember the noun might be singular). Open Notepad (you can simply punch in notepad in the shell) Display only processes that have a name “Notepad” Once you can there’s only one instance of Notepad running, close it with PowerShell! (Verb would be Stop) Confirm with Shell there are no more Notepad processes running Display last 10 lines of C:\windows\setupact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#1] [#2] – Help</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-1-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 16:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-for-it-professionals-1-help/</guid>
      <description>About files solve issue If after running Update-Help you don’t have About topics, you might want to manually download them and extract the archive to the root of:
C:\Windows\System32\WindowsPowerShell\v1.0\en
PowerShell help – Exercises PowerShell is great in working with CSV files. Can you find help for any CSV related commands (you will need to use a wildcard)
Can you tell what’s a difference between ConvertTo-CSV and Export-CSV commands
We often need to review event logs – which command would allow you to retrieve event logs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying software with GPO</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/deploying-software-with-gpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 14:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/deploying-software-with-gpo/</guid>
      <description>Having software consistently deployed across the fleet of computers is one of the key points that can be automated.
If I have a choice (and it makes sense), I will always choose GPO over any other solution because it’s embedded into Active Directory thus not requiring installation, learning and maintenance of additional management tool.
MSI – Software Installation One of the main advantages of MSI installers is that in 99% of cases you can just use the “Software Installation” option in GPO, and GPO will take care of the silent installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare Hyper-V template of Windows Server 2016/2019</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-hyper-v-template-of-windows-server-2016-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-hyper-v-template-of-windows-server-2016-2019/</guid>
      <description>Deploying a new server is always fun! Well, at least the part after ISO download, installation, patching. Having said that, why not create a template so that you jump right into the fun?
So we are essentially going to create a preconfigured VHDX file that can be attached to the newly created VM, and it will take you straight to the login screen.
What’s needed Windows server or Windows 10 with Hyper-V role and management tools enabled Windows Assessment and Deployment Toolkit (ADK) – I always pick the latest version available, at the moment of writing this – Windows 10, version 1903 – is latest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restarting VSS Writers with PowerShell script</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 18:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/restarting-vss-writers-with-powershell-script/</guid>
      <description>VSS Writers are responsible for backups – if they stop working, then backups might fail. The solution to that is restarting VSS Writers, but the problem here is that there are many, and at least out of the box, there’s no mechanism to make this automatic… but there’s PowerShell.
I’m not interested in your code, I just want to restart these VSS Writers In that case, head on to: mygithub, use the code and run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring – why you need it</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/monitoring-why-you-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/monitoring-why-you-need-it/</guid>
      <description>It’s Friday. 5.20PM. So close to the long weekend. Monday is bank holiday – thus three days off. Very happy Friday.
You’re going to the server room to check some minor details. Upon opening the main door, you can feel that cold breeze and characteristic noise of hundreds of spinning fans. You quickly skim through all flashy lights, as it’s a good habit.
And then you notice there’s something wrong. An orange light – why is there an orange light?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The automation process stages</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/the-automation-process-stages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 07:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/the-automation-process-stages/</guid>
      <description>This will be a high level experience I’ve been gaining whenever automating manual processes.
What does it mean to automate? Simply put, is to remove a person from equation in order to complete the task. It can go as far as automating the whole process, or just part of it. The main goal here is to release the resource – that is a person’s time and energy – and redirect it toward something more valuable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sysadmin’s tools – what I have installed on my laptop</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/sysadmins-tools-what-i-have-installed-on-my-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 20:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/sysadmins-tools-what-i-have-installed-on-my-laptop/</guid>
      <description>We need tools to make our work. Either it’s notepad and paper, a hammer (for server’s hard reset… just joking) or some sophisticated and bespoke peace of hardware – we as professionals need tools to make our work better, or even possible.
Since working as IT person, there are many software tools I need to do my day to day tasks, thus here’s the list of pieces of software I’ve been finding useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 summary</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/2018-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 13:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/2018-summary/</guid>
      <description>Here we are, again. Same symbolic time of the year.
I find it perfect to review the past 12 months and have a think about it.
I broke it down into three sections – professional, personal and what didn’t work out. So, let’s go!
Professional Learnt PowerShell – I think it was the biggest achievement career wise this year. It’s hard to put this in formalised matter, or any sort of figure – but the change of my mindset is the biggest one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup Exec – cataloging multiple tapes with a single tape drive</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/backup-exec-cataloging-multiple-tapes-with-a-single-tape-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/backup-exec-cataloging-multiple-tapes-with-a-single-tape-drive/</guid>
      <description>Recently I’ve had a request to restore a certain backup from the old backup tapes. We’ve had a new Backup exec installation which didn’t have the catalogue/record of these tapes nor the actual tape drive to recover them – I knew it was going to be one in the world task. And the hell it was.
Locating tapes in the storage unit was a pure joy – no need to go to the gym after this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Windows Server as iSCSI target with ESXi</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/use-windows-server-as-iscsi-target-with-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/use-windows-server-as-iscsi-target-with-esxi/</guid>
      <description>The task: to move a virtual machine from one ESXi to another. The ESXis are on two completely separate networks. VM size is 5.5 TB, with one file being 5TB.
The problem: VM cannot be started due to maxed out resources. There’s no NAS or any other means of storage where the files could be transferred to. From previous experience, I knew that transfer over SSH or USB would be well too slow, as the task was time critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolve IP and DNS with Powershell tool</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-tool-resolve-ip-and-dns/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been asked to prepare a simple tool which would:
Resolve IP address or DNS Return all results to table Import addresses from a file The reason behind was to check how IP/DNS records change over the period of time, therefore there was a need for something like that:
A file with all addresses in question Tool which could import all these addresses and resolve them Save the results into a new file Once having at least a couple of files, the results could be compared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Windows Update fix</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/ultimate-windows-update-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 22:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/ultimate-windows-update-fix/</guid>
      <description>The reason I manage hundreds of workstations working on various Windows versions. As we know, Windows (and other Microsoft’s software) is updated monthly. While usually the process is just working fine, sometimes it simply doesn’t want to work.
And yes, probably Google is your best friend here… but really, who has time to search for the solution, and apply it, manually, if there is more than 1 computer?
Use the script I used technet, different posts and own knowledge of fixing that kind of issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell – resolve full names to usernames from CSV file</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 14:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/powershell-resolve-full-names-usernames-csv-file/</guid>
      <description>It’s unbelievable how long it took me to figure out this simple Powershell script, but yet it does the trick :).
Often you receive a request to do a certain action with a bunch of accounts, and (obviously) the list provided contains the full names rather usernames. Pain to do it manually, but yet we can utilise Powershell here.
What you need: CSV file, with only one column, and the header of the column must be called “Name”, if you prefer to use something different, simply amend Name in line 6 to reflect your header.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need for energy – my short story of running</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/need-energy-short-story-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 21:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/need-energy-short-story-running/</guid>
      <description>This a quick story how sysadmin started running. I hope it will inspire you to do something with your body, mind and people around you. Yes, because once you’ll start feeling better, others around you will start feeling better as well.
Just a little over 6 months ago… That was November – rainy, windy and cold November. I was exhausted after months of pushing forward the work load. Our team was going through fundamental changes, and the last months towards November were nerve wracking, and there was no light at the end of the tunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add any drivers to Windows – on example of GPU drivers</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/add-any-drivers-to-windows-on-example-of-gpu-drivers/</guid>
      <description>Today we are going to inject drivers into the Windows image with the help of built-in tools in Windows.
What do you need? Just a few things:
Any hardware to which you’d like drivers to be added to Reference computer with the hardware attached to it Drivers Windows image which is going to be deployed I think there’s not much to explain, so let’s analyse the actual process.
What we are going to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you check email every 2 minutes? Start batching your tasks</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/start-batching-your-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/start-batching-your-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Bump. A new email has just arrived. Have to check it. Now. I might reply to it earlier, but need to read it now.
Seriously, why?
While being on top of every single thing might sound super productive, it’s not. Being busy doesn’t mean that you’re productive. Being busy means you’re busy, got nothing to do with effectiveness.
This is the reason why you’d like to play it smart, and to organise your job into batches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PNPUTIL – how to add drivers to the Windows image</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/mastering-pnputil-add-drivers-windows-image/</guid>
      <description>Drivers – that’s what makes a harmony between hardware and software. Appropriate drivers can make a huge difference between computer’s performance, stability and even temperature. Therefore it’s super important to make sure you’ve got up-to-date files included with your image or Windows installation.
We are going to review PNPUTIL tool – the versatile tool for handling drivers within the Windows.
Why do you need PNPUTIL? Yes, why bother with some command line tool (PNPUTIL is command line only) when there are dedicated installers and device manager?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Saturday is best to start new hobby.</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/why-saturday-is-best-to-start-new-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 06:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/why-saturday-is-best-to-start-new-hobby/</guid>
      <description>“I’m going to lose 10 KG”
“I’ll start exercising”
“I’ll crack on with my studies and get a better job”
Can you recall any of these? We prefer to set ourselves goals within certain time frame, like beginning of the year, month or week. That sort of fresh-start gets extra power as a statement, allows us to easily cut off the imperfect past from the all new and wonderful future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare Windows 10 1607 image</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/prepare-windows-10-1607-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later every company will come to the point when using standard Windows image is just not enough. Manual installation, fetching all updates or installing software etc. etc. takes time, and in IT, we really can use that time for something way more productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you even back up?</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/do-you-even-back-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 20:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/do-you-even-back-up/</guid>
      <description>It’s early Monday – the time between the coffee and checking emails – you realise everything’s gone. Files. Videos of your children since they were born. Years of company’s spreadsheets. Gone. It’s not going to be a good week, for sure.
There are 2 kinds of people… According to one of the IT jokes, there are two kinds of people: ones who do back up, and the ones who will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog is changing</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/blog-is-changing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 07:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/blog-is-changing/</guid>
      <description>My idea of this place has been changing since I’ve brought it up. It wasn’t even my first blog, in fact, it was a third one. But the main difference was I wanted to get to the world this time. Don’t just write for the sake of writing.
Very first version of this website was more like a business card or a CV, rather than a blog. I don’t say how proud I was, but also must admit how wrong I was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m really missing time before the Internet.</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/im-really-missing-time-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 19:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/im-really-missing-time-internet/</guid>
      <description>Because software was working without the need of downloading tons of patches. Why do we actually need to update software in the first place?
In the past, the only way to obtain a software was by delivering the physical media to the recipient. There was a cost of media itself and shipment (and probably much more of which I’m not aware of), it couldn’t be cheap. While comparing to the current times, it is just a matter of uploading an update to the server and push to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On time – to be or not to be</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/on-time-to-be-or-not-to-be/</guid>
      <description>We live in a time driven world. We to try to maximise 24 hours every day. Time wasting is not an option.
Therefore we try to squeeze as much as possible in a schedule. Beginning from very morning.
Every morning we start fairly the same, fulfilling daily ritual. Make up, news, coffee – ready, steady, go – everything what make us ready to make a public appearance .
So it’s 8 am, and we are certainly ready to leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less is more</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/less-is-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 17:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/less-is-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a cram-full world, full of anything we could possibly imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a choice is a great thing – I can pick stuff which really suits myself. In case I need, say, a teal corner 4 seater bed sofa, it’s just a matter of time and money I am prepared to spend, until I get one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what happens when I don’t have too many options? When there are 2 things which really suit me, but say, I’ve got space just for 1 sofa?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The kill joy, ready made type</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 22:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/the-kill-joy-ready-made-type/</guid>
      <description>What an easy life when you are an ignorant!
Dull face. Knows all football matches. Actually, this fellow made an art from sitting in front of a TV with a 4-for-£4 pack and trying to prove that this is his life passion. I think I could made another passion from observing clouds in the garden. I would watch them for hours while they change their shapes, move around in the sky, still sitting in the chair and observing them pointlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27 was a great number</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/27-was-a-great-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 21:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/27-was-a-great-number/</guid>
      <description>but I’m certain that 28 will be even better!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps, and their impact on the smart phone</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/apps-impact-smart-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 09:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/apps-impact-smart-phone/</guid>
      <description>When we buy a new phone, manufacturers advertise it always as a super fast with superb colours and a long lasting battery.
Usually it’s true, which we can confirm just after the unboxing ritual when we hold our brand new device in the hands.
It’s shiny, without scratches, with a specific smell, plus it’s really fast and battery lasts very long.
Until… we actually start using the phone, by this I mean installing the whole lot of our favourite apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overloaded</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/overloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 09:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/overloaded/</guid>
      <description>Recently I’ve been writing about information overload. That we should avoid it, select only the best information.
Oh well, I have overloaded myself recently.
I slept 24 hours over the last 2 days! From 8 PM till 8AM. Children don’t sleep that much. My last 2 days had been like: Wake up, shower, work, coffee, home, dinner, coffee, sleep.
Exciting, isn’t it?
For the past 2 days my memory was like ROM – Read Only Memory – mission was to think clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever floats your boat…</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/whatever-floats-your-boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 21:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/whatever-floats-your-boat/</guid>
      <description>How many times I’ve put my all enthusiasm into something, being convinced that it was the right thing.
Hundreds, maybe thousands of times.
How many time afterwards I have realised that my belief was completely wrong. Like 100% wrong. Like back to front feeling.
I think the most difficult is the moment of making a decision. That very moment when it’s time to commit to a long standing decision. The second when it’s time to reveal self and go public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headphones</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 21:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/headphones/</guid>
      <description>At home while writing, photo editing or just for fun. At work when I need to focus and be effective. At the time when I need a boost or completely opposite – when looking for a way to calm down. Headphones accompany me throughout the day.
There is something about sound that keeps me going. When I need to keep up and focus on something certain, I listen to some energy energetic music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-investment</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/self-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 22:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/self-investment/</guid>
      <description>I’m crazy about few things in my life. One of them is self-investment. Something what I do entirely for myself, because I am convinced that it will be beneficial to me, eventually.
At the beginning of my IT journey, I sacrificed a lot of time. There were whole weekends with computer as well as late nights during a week. I wasn’t aware that this could have been an actual investment, that I was working towards bettering my future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routine</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 22:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/routine/</guid>
      <description>They say that habits are our second nature. Things which we do repeatedly are like pre-programmed functions which trigger specific time or action.
Morning coffee. I simply cannot start the day without a cup of a real coffee. That was the reason why I bought the actual bean to coffee machine, because of the taste and smell of real coffee. Prepared in the exact way I like it.
This week I’ve ran out of the time in the morning and couldn’t make my favourite coffee, so I used the instant one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rely</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/rely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/rely/</guid>
      <description>Trust, hope, relationship. Words which make us feel good, because we can rely on others.
I remember when sometime ago, I needed to push a new software to about 50 computers. As always, with that kind of operation, there was a very limited time to do this.
In normal situation, there is deployment solution in place – a server which distributes the software in an automated way. Obviously, as an administrator I need to prepare the whole process – finding installers, commands and switches for these software and even writing scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No pain, no gain.</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/no-pain-no-gain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 21:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/no-pain-no-gain/</guid>
      <description>How many times petty things have ruined your day? Or people? Or, even, yourself? Just admit it.
We can take a lot. Our minds are like massive hard drives which store data in a form of memories, feelings and thoughts.
Did you know that a human is able to erase certain bad memories or push them right back, deep in our subconscious? For example, women are going though unbelievable pain while giving a birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/share/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 22:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/share/</guid>
      <description>I remember like when I was 10-ish and had been trying to fix my first computer. There was no Internet, there was no one really to ask for advice or share the knowledge with me. It took me days, and at the very end, I found that I didn’t have essential drivers to make my computer really usable. Did I mention that the Internet wasn’t available yet?
I had to figure this out, and it took me ridiculous amount of time to achieve such a basic task like reinstalling an operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/influence/</guid>
      <description>A friend visited us yesterday. There was a nice cake, coffee, dinner and conversations thoughtout the night.
Suddenly the ladies started to talk about navigation apps on mobile devices. K. was complaining about high data usage during browsing on the Internet. J. suggested her to try Here maps as it is free and allows to download the maps, therefore data is completely not needed for navigation to work, plus it is really accurate app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do something different</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/do-something-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/do-something-different/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I am so deep in my thoughts that I have no notion of what time of the day is. I know I should be doing something, anything but wasting my time… Life is too short to waste time but all the possibilities somehow don’t even cross my mind.
Do you get the same feeling where you can literally stare at the wall opposite while the time stands still? It’s a horrible feeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silence</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 19:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/silence/</guid>
      <description>The world is loud. It’s shouting though. Being expressive and extrovert is the key to the success this times. It doesn’t matter whether the person is good or positive.
I think we’ve got used to being bombarded on daily basis, everyone and everything want to share with us. It’s up to us whether we’d like to take any of these screams on board, or just ignore them. And obviously, the question is – how much we can accumulate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joy of crossing</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/the-joy-of-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 20:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/the-joy-of-crossing/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a good memory. I can remember different things quite easily, organise and plan them in my mind. A serious and complex task is not a big deal to me, as long as I can understand it. At times I can be annoying (I guess some might say that), by asking many questions, as understanding of each step is a baseline to completing every task correctly.
But there is something magical in writing down the tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 19:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/process/</guid>
      <description>“We are in the process of management change” “The company is in the process of implementing new policies” etc. etc. This is quite a normal term and we don’t pay attention to it, instead we just take this information on board. Whether we like the changes, it’s entirely up to us, despite the fact often we don’t notice any changes in practice. But people are going through “process of a change” as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notification</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 19:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/notification/</guid>
      <description>I carry with me 2 phones – personal one and work one. On the first one, I store only personal stuff, while on the 0ther one everything what is work related.
I have been using my phones like probably most of the people – putting them on vibration while in the restaurants, office etc. so that the phones wouldn’t annoy people around me. But, something’s changed when I was sent for a business trip abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A winner!</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/a-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 21:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/a-winner/</guid>
      <description>We are all winners, undoubtedly. Whatever we do, whenever we create an action – we must win.
Well, not really.
Since the childhood we are taught and pushed to be the best. Get a grade A or B, at least C. Like the D, E or even F don’t exist. We are pushed through countless tests and exams, and being challenged on daily basis.
And there is always somebody, who in a good faith has to say that “you won” even though we actually did not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 21:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/spam/</guid>
      <description>Spam. Spam everywhere. There isn’t a day without it. Without bombarding us with plenty of information. Way too much of information.
While the original – email spam – is well handled by email providers, the other sources are not.
On social media – there is plenty of shared stuff which someone (I hope so!) thought was worth of sharing. News is all over the place – starting from daily free newspapers, through radio and TV and ending up on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s get retar… Started!</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/lets-get-retar-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 21:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/lets-get-retar-started/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts. Ideas. Things which happen in my head for hours, days, sometimes even longer. My brain is constantly thinking, analysing and making decisions, almost 24/7. The problem is – I don’t share… but I really want to.
Some time ago I’ve made a decision to create my own website where I could share my thoughts and where they would stay like carved in the stone.
When I reflect on the past year (this is since I brought up my website) I have published less than 10 (TEN!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Smartphone era, yet?</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/post-smartphone-era-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 17:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/post-smartphone-era-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Apple (and other big brands) recorded a drop of a smartphone sells. First time in over 10 years. Does it mean something is ending? I’d call it a big change. But let me take you step by step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free ride</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/free-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 12:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/free-ride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing really makes me angrier than so called friends who remember about you only when they need something. They just wait to get free ride from you – because what’s a point to pay, if they can get it for free instead?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why certification matters?</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/why-certification-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/why-certification-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gained most of my experience by doing and working things out. Quite often I was reinventing the wheel and discovering already discovered lands. Well, that gave me a lot practice, and no doubts, made me who I am now. But how could I actually proof my skills?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right people</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 18:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>Each of us has some ideal places, songs, people and the way how the morning coffee should be prepared. Sometimes the way how negative situations happen describe the way our day, week, life look like. The way we are.
Funnily enough, very often those things or people are just happening around us, the way we often don’t even notice it. We often can only notice the result of all those things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to utilise a computer’s desktop</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/how-to-utilise-a-computers-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/how-to-utilise-a-computers-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a computer, tablet, or mobile phone. And we usually have some wallpaper set on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, we set family, pets, beautiful landscapes or build quotes as our wallpaper. And this is fine, because this is the reason why the wallpaper was invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience, that’s what really matters</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/what-really-matters-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 19:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/what-really-matters-experience/</guid>
      <description>How can you cut the cost of hardware from £200 to £30? And how to avoid unnecessary money and time waste? You need somebody who thinks out of the box, is determined and the most important – has tons of experience. Below you can see how I was gaining experience and how it helped me to be where I am right now. I always considered myself as the guy who’s got practical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It happened – I ordered my first DSLR.</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/it-happened-i-ordered-my-first-dslr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 20:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/it-happened-i-ordered-my-first-dslr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I look backwards, I have always been fascinated by a photography for quite a long time. But it really hit me about 4 years ago, when I bought some Panasonic camera with 16x zoom. It was only at that particular time that I thought zoom was the most important feature of a camera. Well, I can now say that it is cool to have zoom, but without vibration reduction you cannot do much on long focal length.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://kamilpro.com/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 06:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kamilpro.com/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Every proper project should have the “Hello world!”, so does mine ;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
