<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>invoke - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</title>
        <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/invoke/</link>
        <description>invoke - Tag - Kamil Procyszyn</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:57:20 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kprocyszyn.github.io/tags/invoke/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#19] – Websites and APIs</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:57:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-19-websites-and-apis/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[PowerShell is a great server automation tool, but what about Internet and any other web served services?
As it turns out, PowerShell is great in scrapping websites and consuming APIs – and it’s been one of the main development areas of the tool in the last couple of years.
In this lesson we are going to see how to use PowerShell to download files, scrap websites, discover links.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#17] – Scripting part 4 – parameters, running remotely and formatting</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-17-scripting-part-4-parameters-running-remotely-and-formatting/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:32:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-17-scripting-part-4-parameters-running-remotely-and-formatting/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the last part of scripting series, we will make the script to be able to query remote machines, e.g. servers.
We will also check how to add parameters to the script (and configure the default value of parameter) so that user will able to pass the parameter name like in a standard PowerShell cmdlet.
Finally, we are going to format the script so that it looks more reliable and make some refactoring so that the logic is simpler.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>PowerShell for IT Professionals [#10] – Remote management with PowerShell</title>
    <link>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://kprocyszyn.github.io/powershell-for-it-professionals-10-remote-management-with-powershell/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this lesson we’re going to learn how to do one-to-one and one-to-many remote management with PowerShell. There’s no need for telnet, ssh or psexec as PowerShell has its own protocol that’s built in right into Windows. We will look at how to create interactive sessions and send commands to multiple servers at once.
Exercises Notes Enable-Psremoting Enter-PSSesion ps-svr1 Hostname Get-Service GIP # I can even run commands that are not available on my source machine Get-ADDomainController Get-ADUser Exit or Exit-PSSession # Caution about double hoping Invoke-Command Invoke-Command -computerName ps-svr1 -command { get-service} # Invoke command executes commands on the remote comptuers and brings back the results # Can you tell a difference?]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
